<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Geographer In Nature</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Geographer In Nature</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>nlrx - The best R package for running NetLogo simulation</title>
      <link>/2019-03-18-nlrx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019-03-18-nlrx/</guid>
      <description>IntroFrom the previous blog, you might have noticed the rationale of using high performance computing (HPC), and how fast it is to obtain results compared to our local machines. Having installed all the software requirements on the HPC, today’s post is to simulate a NetLogo model of my Ph.D work in R using an nlrx package(https://ropensci.github.io/nlrx/).
nlrx has promoted its uniqueness for adopting .XML to excecute files that contain various conditions (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to load gdal packages on the HPC?</title>
      <link>/2019-03-10-how-to-load-gdal-packages-on-the-hpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019-03-10-how-to-load-gdal-packages-on-the-hpc/</guid>
      <description>Overviewsystem에 설치하려는 R의 특성로컬컴퓨터에서는 적용이 용이하나 클러스터에서는 적용불가. 이유는 R이 클러스터 전체환경을 바꾸려는 시도를 하기 때문.따라서 사용자 내부환경에서 R 패키지를 설치하게 되었음.ProcedureLoad minicondamodule load miniconda3-4.5.4-gcc-5.4.0-hivczbzInstall R in a new environment in renv2conda create -p renv2conda install RActivate R on renv2source activate /home/hs621/renv2Install desired R packages: sf, sp, tidyverseconda install -p /home/hs621/renv2 R r-sf r-sp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fill in missing data</title>
      <link>/2018-10-06-how-to-fill-in-missing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-10-06-how-to-fill-in-missing-data/</guid>
      <description>Filling missing data = ImputationHow should we deal with missing data? Should we remove them or keep them?  If NA is hardly noticed in the whole dataset, we can simply ignore them in our analysis by using na.rm = T. If not, then we need to do something to fill the gap.
In statistical terms, the process of replacing(filling) a gap is defined as imputation. There are various ways to imputate missing data, but since my focus is on time-series data, it has to at least take into account the (seasonal) trend to minimise possible errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to format numbers as fixed width, with leading zeros</title>
      <link>/2018-05-31-how-to-format-numbers-as-fixed-width-with-leading-zeros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-05-31-how-to-format-numbers-as-fixed-width-with-leading-zeros/</guid>
      <description>As one of the R Users, I feel quite annoying when I encounter string files which have have counters at the end myfile_1.jpg, myfile_2.jpg,....,myfile_11.jpg.  Why does this bother me? Simple. This is because the sorting system in the R environment only sorts files from their higher digits. For example, in R, the files are sorted in this order: myfile_1.jpg, myfile_11.jpg, ..., myfile_19.jpg, myfile_2.jpg, myfile_20.jpgand so on. But for analytic purposes, we need our first nine files ordered correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>